Finding Aid for Kelsey Museum of Archaeology papers 1890-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Kelsey Museum papers, 1891-1948; 1.3 linear feet
  - Topical Files
    - Excavation Numbers-notes (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Exhibits
      - Equipment notes (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Angell Hall, Newberry Hall [lists, records] (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Rackham Building Pottery Foster & Haile, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Rackham Building, von Ketteler, Maud Ledyard, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Rackham Building, Mirrors, Bronze by Plumer, Stelae, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Falconer's Reports [Harold Falconer], 1926 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Films-cinema U/M Extension, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Films-Slides Records Worksheets (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Glass check (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Hausler, Joseph M., 1938 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Inscriptions in Kelsey Mss. [lists, notes] (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Inscriptions in Kelsey Mss. [worksheets] (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - von Ketteler, Maud Ledyard, 1926; 1928; 1942 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Latin Literature (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Lectures on Karanis
      - 1941 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 1941, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Lecture: Arts and Crafts of a Provincial Town of Roman Egypt. Michigan Academy of Sciences., 1943 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Leica, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Loan Exhibits, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Maps (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Marble in Building Materials Collection (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous items, 1941; 1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Model for Corpus of Pompeii Painting (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Inventory Corrections to Mosaiques de la Gaule et de l'Afrique, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Paper trimmer (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Papyri Checking, 1924-1928 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Photographs [not Museum], 1891; 1896; 1906-1909; 1926 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Photographs once hung on old Library stairs (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Photographs and slides, notes on cataloging (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Photographs, special (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Plant and personnel protection, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Plastics, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Postcards (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Pottery (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Printing samples (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Publications of excavations, recipients of (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Reports, 1937-1946 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Reports, notes for, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Requisition notes, 1942; 1944 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Marvin Ross, Walter's Art Gallery, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Allan Rowe, Excavation Journal, circa 1926 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Scipio Bust, 1908-1909 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Seleucia Excavations Material put away, June 1942 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Shipment Records, 1928; 1938 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Stelae Terenouthis Classification (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Surveying notes (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Van Ingen, Pottery and Publication, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Vester, Fr. & Company, 1920-1921 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Viereck, Paul, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Visitors to Museum, 1938-1941 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Widdecomb Furniture Forgeries, 1907 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Woodbridge, Frederick J., 1924-1925 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Works Progress Administration, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous items (Box 4)
    - Photograph Album, circa 1970s (Box 4)
- Robert H. McDowell papers, 1929-1938; 0.5 linear feet
  Papers, 1929-1938, of Robert H. McDowell, Research Associate in Mesopotamian Archaeology and Research Associate in Greek and Latin at the University of Michigan; member of University sponsored expeditions at Tell Umar, Seleucia and Tigris; active in British Military Intelligence, W.W.I and American Intelligence, W.W.II; author; letters, manuscripts, miscellaneous papers.
  This small collection highlights work done in Seleucia from 1936 to 1937.
  - Topical Files
    - Misc. Papers, 1935-1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Roman coins (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Clark Hopkins Mss. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Clark Hopkins Mss., 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - City Plans and Topography around the city (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Catalogue of Photographs, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Figurine Notes and Pottery (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Lists and indices [includes Yeivin material] (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Materials of graves S. Yeivin Seasons, 1929-1930; 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Misc. notes (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - General notes (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Objects, 1/12/1934-2/5/1934 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Objects, illustrating daily life in the city (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Various objects, June 23, 1933-January 12, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Enoch Ernest Peterson papers, 1924-1962; 3.5 linear feet
  The major portion of these records consists of correspondence, principally covering the period when Peterson was in charge of the University of Michigan sponsored excavations (1926-1935). Also pertaining to that period are reports, financial records and statements, and notebooks. Peterson's general museum files (1938-1962) are small by contrast: this may be the result of weeding out material before the records were placed in the attic. Also, many Museum or "Peterson" files had been stored in the Registrar's office at the time of the "housecleaning"; they are now being used as reference material. Included among Peterson's papers are several periodicals and books: however the collection is notably devoid of biographical material or personal mementos of any kind.
  - Early Files, 1924-1927
    - Asia Minor, 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Carthage, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Karpinski; wainwright n.d., 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Financial, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Karanis
    - American Consular Service. Gordon P. Merriam, 1933-1935 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - American Express Company, 1927; 1934-1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Antiquities, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Antiquities Department-Iraq, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Askren, David L., 1928; 1930-1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Automobiles, 1927-1931; 1933 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Boak, Arthur E.R.
      - 1927-1929 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - 1930 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - 1931-1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Bonner, Campbell
      - 1927-1931 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - 1932-1935 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Butler, Orma Fitch, 1929-1933 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - B-General Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Christensen, J. C., 1931-1935 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Division Records, 1927-1933 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - D-N General Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Re: Golovko, Simeon, 1930; 1932; 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Kelsey, Francis W.
      - May 1925-June 1926 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - August-December 1926 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - January-May 1927 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Kelsey Report, December 31, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Notes regarding work in Egypt and related material [Kelsey], 1925 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Reports, general. [Kelsey], 1927 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Chemical Fertilizers, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Wainwright matter [Kelsey], 1927 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Letters from workers, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Memorandum No. 17, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Misc. Items, 1931-1934 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Misc. Material, 1924-1926 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Misc. Requests, 1926-1934 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - de Prorok, Byron, 1927-1928; 1933 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Report, 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Richards, F. S., 1936 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Robbins, Frank E.
      - undated, 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - 1933 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - 1934-1935, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Robinson, David M., 1927-1928 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Ruthven, Alexander, 1933-1935 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Sample of Camp Accounts, 1930-1931 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Sanders, Henry A.
      - 1927 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - 1928-1930, 1933-1935 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Schumann, Verne B., 1928-1930 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Swain, George, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Terentieff, Ivan, 1927-1928; 1930-1931; 1935 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Visitors, 1930s (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Visitors' Guestbook, 1926-1928 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Wainwright, G. A., 1926-1927 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Waterman, Leroy n.d., 1928 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Windows [drawings) Amundsen, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Winnesheik County State Bank, 1927-1928 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Winter, John G., 1929; 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Yeivin, Samuel, 1926-1928 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Papers from the Field
    - Contents of Envelopes NTH (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - List of Objects (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
    - Misc. Notes, lists (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Notebook (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Documents, 1924; 1927; 1935 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - American Express Vouchers, 1931-1934 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Letters, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Museum Files
    - Abd El Lateef Ahmed Aly, 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Agriculture Museum, Cairo, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - American Egyptian Society, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - American Research Center in Egypt, 1950-1955 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Antiquities (Dept. of)
      - 1928-1932 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - 1933-1935 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - 1939, 1946; 1950 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Antiquities (Dept. of) Battiscombe Gunn, 1929-1931 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - A-General Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Budget-Form C Misc. Documents, 1952-1954 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - B-General Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Casts (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Conservation of Objects, 1952; 1954 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Cummer Collection Arms and Armor (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Exhibit Life in a Roman Town in Egypt (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Exhibitions. Items Loaned [photos] The Neville Collection, 1941; 1949 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - C-E General Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - F-G General Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Harden, Donald B., 1932-1933; 1936; 1938; 1945-1948 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - H; J-General Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Kelsey Museum By-Laws Advisory Board, misc. (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - College of L.S.& A. Misc., 1953 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Locking doors (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Map Index Additional numbers (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Memos; re: Roger's Casts, Swain negatives, 1933; 1937 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - K; M-General Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Papyri, 1928-1934; 1952 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Papyri misc. Photographs (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Pottery (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Press Reports, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Publications Records and Reports re: Excavations (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Askren, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Boak, 1924-1925 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Kelsey, 1924-1925; 1927 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Misc., 1926 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Yeivin, 1924-1927 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - N-P; R-General Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Sanders, Henry A., 1931 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Senior Citizens Guild Lectures, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Shier, Louise, Undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Storage Records in the Museum (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Subject Headings Accounts, 1955-1956; 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - S-General Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Tano, Frank, 1938-1943; 1945 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Tano, Frank re: $580 purchase and 1945 purchase, 1935-1938 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Topography and Architecture (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Triangulation chart (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Unesco Nubia Project, 1960-1961 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Winter, John G., 1927; 1936; 1938; 1940; 1942; 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - T; V-W; Y-General Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Financial Records
    - Account # 33355 Kelsey Museum Exhibits (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Ad Hoc Committee, 1954-1955 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Appointments (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Budget, 1957-1962 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Budget Merit Increases, 1953-1961 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - College of L.S.& A., 1967 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Equipment Non-expendable, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Equipment Inventory, 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Executive Committee, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Expenditures Itemized, 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Personnel Records, 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Promotions, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Publications Notes (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Rehabilitation-Kelsey Museum (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Sabbatical leaves, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Salaries, 1955; 1957-1960 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Course 51
    - Course 51 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - First Semester, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Second Semester, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - First Semester, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Course Notebook (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Guidebooks; Catalogs
    - Guidebooks; catalog (Box 8)
- Louise Adele Shier papers, 1923-1987; 4.5 linear feet
  The correspondence and documents in the Kelsey Museum Business series touch upon exhibits and collections; however the material shows no clear development of exhibits and in many cases lacks complete documentation on acquisition of collections. Materials in the Publications series includes notes, drafts, and working materials for Shier's book, Terracotta Lamps from Karanis, Egypt, and correspondence with Eleanor Husselman describing her work on Enoch Peterson's manuscript on Karanis, published in 1979. Also included are some personal files, political materials, records of the Women's Research Club and a series of vouchers and receipts from the dig at Dibsi Faraj, Syria.
  - Kelsey Museum Business, 1923-1976
    - Boak Library (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Budget, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Coin Enlargement (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Collection Notes (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Coptic Embroidery-Ellsberg (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Coptic Photographs - Infra-red (Box 5)
    - Coptic Textiles--Metropolitan Museum (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Coptic Textiles--Walters Art Gallery (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence
      - John Pedley, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence; notes, 1923; 1948; undated; 1965; 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Embroidered hanging; notes, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Exhibits
      - Glass, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Greek Pottery; notes (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Karanis: Records of an Excavation in Egypt (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Karanis: label copy (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Labels (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Metropolitan Museum --loan (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
      - Metropolitan Museum -- loan: First Floor Exhibit (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Metropolitan Museum -- loan: Exhibits Room I (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Metropolitan Museum -- loan: Exhibits Room II (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Metropolitan Museum -- loan: Exhibits Room III (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Museum Science Cataloguing, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Fisher Papyrus-Book of the Dead Label copy and pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Loans
      - Cummer Loan, Albion Loan; notes (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Early Christian Museum of Art (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Villa Hugel, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous notes; manuscripts. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous reports; notes [includes Seleucia] (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous cards, forms (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Museums -- Kalamazoo, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Pope Shenonda Visit (Box 6)
    - Publications (Box 5)
    - Requests--photos; negatives, undated; 1969; 1971; 1974-1975; 1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Report, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Reports, collections, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Valuation (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Varia (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Publications
    - Article in "The Classical Outlook" (Box 5)
    - Book Reviews (Box 5)
    - Egyptian Publications (Box 5)
    - Lamps-Publication
      - Applications for funds publications; miscellaneous, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - John Hayes, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - L. A. Benachi, 1953-1957; 1959 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - L. A. Benachi Collection, 1950-1953; 1961 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Accessions (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Original Drawings, 1959; 1964 (Box 4)
      - Drawings of Potter's Marks, undated (Box 4)
      - Books Plates and Drawings, undated (Box 4)
      - Drawings and Descriptions, undated (Box 4)
      - Misc. Notes, Rubbings, undated (Box 4)
      - Misc. Notes on Layers and Finds, undated (Box 4)
      - Research, Dairaines Collection, undated (Box 4)
      - Misc. Photos, Notes, undated (Box 4)
      - Notes and Mss., undated (Box 4)
      - D. Lamps, Preliminary Copy, undated (Box 4)
      - Figure Lamps, undated (Box 4)
      - Lamps - Numbers from Egypt, undated (Box 4)
      - Lamps - Egyptian Museum, Cairo, Photos and Notes, undated (Box 4)
      - Chronology, undated (Box 4)
      - Research, undated (Box 4)
      - Notes, undated; 6 folders (Box 4)
      - Misc. Drawings, Photos, Maps, undated (Box 4)
      - Lamps, Harden Classification, undated (Box 4)
      - Research, undated; 3 folders (Box 4)
      - Bibliography of Ancient Lamps, 1936 (Box 4)
      - Receipt for Mss, 1978 (Box 4)
      - Dimay, undated (Box 4)
      - Terenouthis, Roman Type XXV, undated (Box 4)
      - Royal Ontario Museum of Archaeology, John Hayes, 1976; 2 folders (Box 4)
      - "The Frog on Lamps from Karanis", 1967; 1972 (Box 4)
      - Preface and List of Maps and Plates (Box 4)
      - Catalogue, 3 folders (Box 4)
      - Drawings (Box 4)
      - Notes (Box 4)
      - Bibliography (Box 4)
      - Preliminaries, i-xx (Box 4)
      - Introduction, 1-11, Discussion of Types, 13-50 (Box 4)
      - Catalogue, 52-166 (Box 4)
      - Notes, 167-187 (Box 4)
      - Chronology, 188-189, Table 190-206, Concordance, 207-210 (Box 4)
      - Indexes - Inscriptions, 211, Representations, 212-213, General 214-219, Bibliography (Box 4)
      - Negatives (Box 4)
      - Original Lamps of Karanis Manuscript, Preface - Introduction (Box 5)
      - Original Lamps of Karanis Manuscript, Catalogue (Box 5)
      - Original Lamps of Karanis Manuscript, Bibliography (Box 5)
      - "Lamps of the Roman Period from University of Michigan Excavations in Egypt" (Box 6)
      - "Lamp Types from Graeco Roman Egypt" (Box 6)
      - "The Frog Lamps of Roman Egypt" (Box 6)
      - "Roman Lamps and Lamp Makers of Egypt" (Box 6)
      - "The Frog and the Cross on Lamps from Karanis" (Box 6)
      - Catalog records, index cards, notes, photographs, and correspondence (Box 7)
      - Notes, drawings, and photographs of various types of lamps (Box 8)
        (includes materials labelled Marks, Delos, Karanis, Delos, Terenouthis, Egypt, Greek, Hellenistic, Christian, and Frog)
      - Photographs of lamps in Cairo, 150 envelopes approximate (Box 9)
        (Photographs are individually foldered and either numbered 52581-52751, 65566-65591 (some numbers missing) or labelled "Provincial Museum"
    - Peterson-Husselman Mss.
      - Karanis manuscripts., 1973-1977 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Elinor Husselman, Undated; 1969-1976 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Elinor M. Husselman Materials (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Matters
    - Personal Files
      - Bay View Association (Box 5)
      - Correspondence, 1917-1987; 3 folders (Box 5)
      - Glacier Hills Residence Association, 1984 (Box 6)
      - Misc. Clippings, Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 5)
      - Notebooks (Box 5)
      - Personal; cards; lists of slides; newspapers (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Photographs (Box 5)
      - Shier Family Records (Box 5)
      - Student files (Box 5)
    - Fourth International Congress of Classical Studies (Box 5)
    - Politics
      - Political Publications, 1920s (Box 5)
      - Republication National Convention, 1928 (Box 5)
    - University of Michigan
      - Publications (Box 5)
      - Women's Research Club
        - Women's Research Club members, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 23)
        - Women's Research Club members, 1960s (Box 5)
      - Women of the University Faculty
        - 1944-1952 (Box 2, Folder 24)
        - 1953-1958 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Vouchers and receipts: I; II; III; IV, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
- John Garrett Winter Papers, 1914-1949; 0.5 linear feet
  Although John Winter was Director of the Kelsey Museum for twenty-one years, the Museum collection contains only one archival storage box of these records. Included is some correspondence with Francis Kelsey, letters and reports concerning the Committee on Research, Museum budgets and miscellaneous material about the Museum. Other Museum related files are housed at the University of Michigan Bentley Historical Library.
  - Papers of John Garrett Winter
    - Kelsey, Francis W., 1914; 1918-1925; 1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Committee on Research, 1941-1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Museum Budget
      - 1939-1943 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1943-1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Museum Varia
      - 1915-1916, 1928-1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 1937-1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Museum Misc., 1937-1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - History of the Bronze Mercury, given by Dr. Hubbard (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Carthage Excavations, 1975; 1979
  - Excavation records
    - Notebook and R. Brown notes (P3B, P3G, P3H) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Notebook and R. Brown notes (P3C) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Notebook and R. Brown notes (P3D) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Notebook and R. Brown notes (P3E) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Notebook and R. Brown notes (P3F) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Notebook and R. Brown notes (P3G) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Notebook and R. Brown notes (P3H) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Notebook and R. Brown notes (P3J) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Notebook and R. Brown notes (P3K) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Notebook and R. Brown notes (P3L) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Notebook and R. Brown notes (P3M) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Notebook and R. Brown notes (P3N) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Notebook and R. Brown notes (P3P) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Notebook and R. Brown notes (P3Q) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Notebook and R. Brown notes (P3Y) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - J. Humphrey stratigraphy notes on squares, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Matrices and charts section (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Duplicate matrices (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Pottery codes (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Pottery buckets (all published) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "A system for quick publication of pottery finds" (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Pottery count-Stager's excavation-good groups-basic counts (for final figures and percentages) (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Pottery counts and weights (#1-179) (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Pottery register (Sheets 1A-202) (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Carthage coins (1-642) (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Original drawings of original pottery sherds (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Original drawings of original pottery sherds (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Original drawings of original pottery sherds (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Volume 1 --Duplicate illustrations of mosaics and gems-prints and negatives (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Volume 1 --Preliminaries-French summaries-Chap. 1 Original MSS (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Volume 1-Chapter 2 Original MSS (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Volume 1-Chapter 3 Original MSS (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Volume 1-Chapter 4 Original MSS (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Notebook (P3V) (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Notebook K2 probe (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Notebook K2W (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Pot Register Summaries (All Published) (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Pottery count-1976 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Blue File-Pottery Summaries Carthage, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Red File-1976 Negatives
    - Box 3A
    - Part 7 Grotius Notesa 1 (Pgs 1-238)
    - 4 groups of photographs
    - Volume 3-Preliminaries and Chapter 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)